The legend no one can forget has become the greatest 3D adventure ever filmed.
Ghosts of the Abyss is a documentary film directed by James Cameron.
With a team of the world's foremost historic and marine experts as well as friend Bill Paxton, James Cameron embarks on an
unscripted adventure back to the wreck of the Titanic where nearly 1,500 souls lost their lives almost a century ago.
Self, played by Bill Paxton.
Self, played by John Broadwater.
Self, played by James Cameron.
Self, played by Charles Pellegrino.
Self, played by Lewis Abernathy.
Self, played by Mike Cameron.
Ghosts of the Abyss (also known as Titanic 3D: Ghosts of the Abyss) is a 2003 American documentary film
directed by James Cameron and produced by Walden Media about the wreck of the RMS Titanic.
It was directed by James Cameron after his 1997 film Titanic.
In August and September 2001, Cameron and a group of
scientists staged an expedition to the Titanic wreck.
They dived in Russian deep submersibles to obtain more
detailed images than anyone had before.
Using two small, purpose-built remotely operated vehicles, the documentary offers glimpses into the
wreck and, with CGI, superimposes the ship's original appearance on the deep-dive images.
The film is narrated by Bill Paxton, who joined Cameron on the expedition
and played Brock Lovett in Cameron's 1997 film Titanic.
The film premiered for IMAX 3D and was nominated for
a BFCA award for Best Documentary.
The submersibles Mir 1 and Mir 2 carried the filming team on 12 dives.
The film explores themes of diving, shipwreck,
titanic, underwater, oceanic expedition.